So, this also nothing but a lot in WMA C.exe because the detectors using the slal been
to two some attacks like laterly move from one machine to another and executing the files
remotely.
We will see that the later executing the fire and all modes and all, but we will explore
that WMA C.exe so what is WMA C.exe the full form also windows management instrumentation
is a command line so that's your side and side we will call the command line windows management
instrumentation command line so this is an utility for in a windows so it will provide
a command line interface for a user so we can just query we can do some management
related stuff like we can if you need how many if you need to access the hardware or software
if you need to query the hardware or software like which windows maintenance you buy we are
using and what is the latest what is the updates we did and what is the disk management
information and what about the users information and we can we can query a few information
we can we can query that we can get some information so probably the detector will be using
this for a gathering some information from the machine like if they update or it's whether
the machine was running in the latest latest window sub data it's a old one and they will
be getting some like information and they will they will do based on a tax based on that
okay also this was used for laterally return moment from one machine to another we if you
can see the see the command here if you want to execute any anything you can go ahead
and you can execute inside the windows machine so if I open so let's let's do this by
executing executing a Calc inside the CMD at exe that we do that do that with that so now
I can see the CEO calculator has been started because I started a process with the Calcaman
also you can execute your malware by process call create some Malcolm CMD or DX like that
so you can execute any program program here basically and if you need to execute anything
in a remote system a remote machine you have to give the remote IP here so if the threat
you can do that by using like if the hardware the confirmation of the machine and they need
to execute the program on another mission they will just use this command note it's a remote
machine IP address and they will create a process call they will execute the will dot EAC
diminishes file into another machine okay so also all they can do lot of things like they
can do a shadow copies we'll see what's a shadow copies and I'm and using WMAC we
can delete the shadow copies also that will be more dangerous we can see everything after
that is why if I say these kind of things will be get confused when creating this let's
land everything on by one and you can you can do a lot and lot of stuff here you can copy
a file from one machine to another so here you can I have listed some of the commands so
you can get lot of information using the WMAC if you need a user account information you
can execute this command you can you can you can get some information let me let me close
that so now you can see it listed I you user accounts they can see everything each and
everything here right and this will give the installed update for your operating operating
system let me copy one more time so I can see now you can see all the installed update
this is a hot six you said it previously and security update I did and the windows updated
this are the few updates that has been installed instead of machine if you need to terminate
some process you can go ahead and you can you can give your executable and you can go ahead
and terminate the process so if you want to if you want to know about the voice versions
or current architectures or anything you can execute this command I will give the commands
in the resource session so don't worry about that so you can go ahead and you can execute
this information so basically WMAC will be used for some information like the management
later things regarding the hardware software this kind of things okay so this will be very
useful when you are doing a real time attacks it is 64 bit and Windows 11 interface evaluation
versions and this version of windows so if the if the versions of sonar blade can go ahead
and do a few more attacks right so the threat I will be using this WMAC for a lot of things
but yep these are the these are the few so we will for they will get many information
regarding the various hardware software everything so they can use this information for
further attacks yeah guys also we seen how they will use for a lateral moment and how
they will execute the pros in one of the way in another machine right so we will hope
of this video and we will continue our discussion in the next video bye bye